<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Crypto on 4rkal</title>
    <link>https://4rkal.com/tags/crypto/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Crypto on 4rkal</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 21:00:30 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://4rkal.com/tags/crypto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ultimate Monero ColdStorage Guide (Feather X Anonero)</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/feathernero/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 21:00:30 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/feathernero/</guid>
      <description>In this comprehensive guide, I will walk you through the process of easily setting up Monero cold storage using an old computer and your smartphone, using animated QR codes. No USB needed!&#xA;Requirements An old laptop/computer with a webcam (to be kept offline). Called offline or cold computer. An android smartphone. Your main computer Required reads Before starting this article you must read:&#xA;Key concepts Monero offline transaction signing details Cold computer setup Your offline computer/laptop will be signing all of the transactions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Easy monero cold storage</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/coldstorage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 18:03:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/coldstorage/</guid>
      <description>In this article I will show you how to &amp;ldquo;easily&amp;rdquo; generate a live archlinux usb with the monero gui pre-installed.&#xA;Requirements An archlinux install A usb Setup In this guide I will show you how to build a custom archlinux iso with monerogui installed. I will not be providing any pre-built images.&#xA;The first thing you will have to do is install archuseriso. You can install it from the aur using this command:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Monero is the ultimate form of a cryptocurrency</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/whymonero/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 20:23:16 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/whymonero/</guid>
      <description>In this article, I will tell you why Monero fits my views of what a cryptocurrency should look like.&#xA;What is Monero? Monero is a decentralized cryptocurrency. It uses a public distributed ledger with privacy-enhancing technologies that obfuscate transactions to achieve anonymity and fungibility. Observers cannot decipher addresses trading Monero, transaction amounts, address balances, or transaction histories.&#xA;Monero works like any other currency but with some privacy and decentralization innovations.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
