<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Crypto on 4rkal</title>
    <link>https://4rkal.com/tags/crypto/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Crypto on 4rkal</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://4rkal.com/4rkal.png</url>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/4rkal.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 18:32:54 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4rkal.com/tags/crypto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introducing CypherGoat - The first open source crypto exchange aggregator</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/launching-cyphergoat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 18:32:54 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/launching-cyphergoat/</guid>
      <description>Swap your crypto at the best rate on the market. Fast, Private, Open source!</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="why-i-built-cyphergoat">Why I built CypherGoat</h2>
<p>Ever since I first got into crypto I have been building products to make using crypto easier. In early 2022 I co-founded <a href="https://dsc.gg/rubytrades">RubyTrades</a> a (kind of p2p) non kyc fiat on ramp that allowed users to buy and sell crypto using PayPal. Although it was not as successful as we had hoped it still gained some traction and I learned a lot from it.
After that I got interested in Monero. I built <a href="https://github.com/4rkal/moneroos">MoneroOS</a> a plug and play live operating system that mines monero on boot. I also built <a href="https://github.com/4rkal/MoneroNodeMonitor">MoneroNodeMonitor</a> and some other projects.</p>
<p>I was always fascinated by cross-chain on chain swaps (like rubic.exchange), so I decided to build something similar, <em>but better</em>.</p>
<h2 id="what-is-cyphergoat">What is CypherGoat?</h2>
<p>It is a <strong>crypto swap aggregator</strong> it automatically finds the <strong>best exchange rates</strong> from our partnered exchange at no extra cost. You can then perform the swap on that exchange, without ever leaving our website!</p>
<h3 id="why-its-cool">Why it&rsquo;s cool</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>KYC-Free</strong> – No personal verification required.</li>
<li><strong>Non-Custodial</strong> – Direct to wallet trading (on chain swaps)</li>
<li><strong>Open Source</strong> – Our web UI is open-source.</li>
<li><strong>User-Friendly for Everyone</strong> – Unlike other aggregators with complex interfaces, CypherGoat has a clean and simple UI, perfect for both beginners and advanced users.</li>
<li><strong>Fast &amp; Seamless</strong> – Just pick your tokens, swap, and receive.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="how-it-works">How it works</h2>
<p>Using CypherGoat is ridiculously simple:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Choose your tokens</strong> – Select the crypto you want to send the one you want to receive and that the amount you want to swap.</li>
<li><strong>Get the Best Rate</strong> – CypherGoat &ldquo;scans&rdquo; exchanges and finds the best deal for you.</li>
<li><strong>Swap &amp; Receive</strong> – Confirm the trade, enter your address, send your funds, and get your swapped crypto in your wallet.</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="final-thoughts">Final thoughts</h2>
<p>Crypto swapping shouldn’t be complicated, and I truly believe CypherGoat makes it easier. If you have thoughts, suggestions, or just want to chat about crypto, let’s connect! You can find me and the growing CypherGoat community on <a href="https://t.me/cyphergoatcom">Telegram</a> and <a href="https://x.com/cyphergoatcom">Twitter</a> .</p>
<p>Head over to <a href="https://cyphergoat">cyphergoat.com</a>, to see the magic ; )</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultimate Monero ColdStorage Guide (Feather X Anonero)</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/feathernero/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 21:00:30 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/feathernero/</guid>
      <description>In this comprehensive guide, I will walk you through the process of easily setting up Monero cold storage using an old computer and your smartphone, using animated QR codes. No USB needed!</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In this comprehensive guide, I will walk you through the process of easily setting up Monero cold storage using an old computer and your smartphone, using animated QR codes. No USB needed!</p>
<h2 id="requirements">Requirements</h2>
<ol>
<li>An old laptop/computer with a webcam (to be kept offline). Called <strong>offline</strong> or <strong>cold</strong> computer.</li>
<li>An android smartphone.</li>
<li>Your main computer</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="required-reads">Required reads</h2>
<p>Before starting this article you <strong>must</strong> read:</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://malvarma.org/before_we_start/what_things_mean.html">Key concepts</a></li>
<li><a href="https://monero.stackexchange.com/questions/2426/offline-transaction-signing-what-are-the-details">Monero offline transaction signing details</a></li>
</ol>
<h2 id="cold-computer-setup">Cold computer setup</h2>
<p>Your offline computer/laptop will be signing all of the transactions. It should always be kept offline i.e cold. It can not be used for other tasks.</p>
<p>I highly recommend that you use a linux distribution and NOT windows for cold storage. Linux is free and opensource. I highly recommend pepermintOS or MX linux as they are lightweight and pretty easy to setup.</p>
<p>I will not be guiding you on how to install [[linux]]. But here are some resourses to help you get started:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://peppermintos.com/guide/downloading/">Installing PeperMintOS</a> &lt;&ndash;  somewhat 32 bit support, lightweight</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://linuxmint-installation-guide.readthedocs.io/en/latest/install.html">Installing LinuxMint</a> &lt;&ndash; better for newer computers</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.makeuseof.com/how-to-install-mx-linux/">Installing MX Linux</a> &lt;&ndash; 32 bit support, pretty lightweight</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="downloading--installing-necessary-software">Downloading &amp; Installing necessary software</h3>
<p>The first thing that we will need to do is download the required software.</p>
<p>We will need <a href="https://featherwallet.org">featherwallet</a></p>
<p>and that&rsquo;s about it.</p>
<h3 id="taking-the-device-offline">Taking the device offline</h3>
<p>It is highly recommended that you disable the wifi and bluetooth modules on your cold computer. This can be by physically detaching the wifi and bluetooth module or disabling it in the bios. The later is less secure if you&rsquo;re going full on <a href="https://i.imgur.com/p5h6STu.jpeg">tinfoilhat</a>.</p>
<p>Here&rsquo;s a guide on how to physically disable them from <a href="https://malvarma.org/cold_wallet/prepare_the_hardware.html">malvarma.org</a></p>
<p>A guide on how to disable it via BIOS can be found by searching your specific hardware on your <a href="https://searx.org/">favorite search engine</a>.</p>
<h3 id="computer-cold-wallet-setup">Computer cold wallet setup</h3>
<p>Now we will have to setup our wallet. Ensure that your device is completely <strong>offline</strong> and then open featherwallet.</p>
<ol>
<li>Click on <code>Create a new wallet</code>. Then click on <code>Next</code>. You will be presented with your seedphrase. <strong>Write it down!! on physical paper</strong>.</li>
<li>Select a name for your wallet and click <code>Next</code></li>
<li>Select a wallet password and click <code>Next</code>.</li>
<li>Now that the wallet is open in the bottom right corner there will be a dot. Click on it and select the offline box and then click <code>Disable all network connections (offline)</code></li>
</ol>
<h2 id="phone">Phone</h2>
<p>We will now be installing the anonero software. We will be using NERO from the ANON/NERO suite.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Download and install fdroid. Apk can be downloaded from the <a href="https://fdroid.org">F-Droid website</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Download and install orbot. Can be installed from google play store <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.torproject.android">here</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Open orbot. Select <code>VPN Mode</code>, click on the onion logo that says <code>start</code></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Open fdroid and in the settings scroll down and enable <code>Use Tor</code> option</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Again in the settings that click on the repositories section and add the following:</p>
<p><code>http://anonero5wmhraxqsvzq2ncgptq6gq45qoto6fnkfwughfl4gbt44swad.onion/fdroid/repo?fingerprint=C5705FF724538F6925B6093517F53C6C6BB6CF82518ED40EB4B8CBBB87DC0D1D</code></p>
<p>Source: <a href="https://anonero.io">anonero.io</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Click on  latest and then search for NERO</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Click on install
That&rsquo;s it ; )</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="updating-nero">Updating NERO</h3>
<p>If you want to update NERO you will have to turn orbot on, open fdroid and refresh the updates tab</p>
<h3 id="nero-setup">NERO setup</h3>
<p>To set up NERO, follow these steps:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>Once NERO is successfully installed, open the application.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Click on <code>RESTORE WALLET</code> option and select <code>RESTORE FROM KEYS</code></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Proceed to establish a node connection. You can find a lot of Monero nodes <a href="https://monero.fail">here</a>.</p>
<p>Random clearnet node:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>http://xmr.monopolymoney.eu:18089</code></li>
</ul>
<p>Random Tor node:</p>
<ul>
<li><code>http://xmrsalty4hg7lq5ci4kzc2xxcic57azapolbunmkiypnmr3wp7uvqnyd.onion:18089</code></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
<p>Copy the node address into the node field. By default you shouldn&rsquo;t need a username or password</p>
<p>By default tor connectivity is enabled in NERO. You can disable it by going into the proxy settings and deleting everything.</p>
<ol start="4">
<li>Click on <code>Connect</code>. It will try connecting. If it fails check your internet connection or try another node</li>
</ol>
<h3 id="importing-view-only-wallet">Importing view-only wallet</h3>
<p>Now you will have to import your wallets <code>Primary address</code> , <code>Secret-View key</code> and <code>Restore height</code> into NERO. To import that info to nero:</p>
<p>On your offline computer open featherwallet and navigate to <code>Wallet</code> then <code>View-Only</code>. Enter your password and click on the <code>Show QR</code></p>
<p>Now in nero in the View only keys screen click on the square icon to scan the qr. Then scan the qr displayed by featherwallet. All the info should be filled in after scanning the qr code. Click <code>Next</code>.</p>
<p>Set a pin. After that your wallet should be imported into NERO.</p>
<h2 id="receiving-monero">Receiving monero</h2>
<p>To receive monero you can follow these steps</p>
<ol>
<li>Open NERO and enter your pin</li>
<li>Click on the receive tab (the one with the qr code icon)</li>
<li>Long hold on the address</li>
<li>Select one of the SubAddreses and click on the copy icon.</li>
<li>Transfer any amount of monero to that address.</li>
</ol>
<p>After 10 confirmations it should be spendable. Proceed to the next step.</p>
<h2 id="signing-transactions">Signing transactions</h2>
<p>Signing/Broadcasting transactions is easy with the NERO/Feather duo. No usbs are needed it is all done via animated QR codes.</p>
<p>To sign/broadcast a transaction follow these steps
On your phone:</p>
<ol>
<li>Open NERO and enter your pin</li>
<li>In the send tab enter the desired address and amount</li>
<li>Click on continue, you should now see an animated QR code.</li>
</ol>
<p>On your cold computer</p>
<ol>
<li>Open feather and enter your password</li>
<li>Click on <code>Tools</code> &gt; <code>Offline transaction signing</code>. You should now see your camera</li>
<li>Show your phone to the computers camera so that it can read the QR code.</li>
<li>After it has been picked up by your computer you should see a QR code displayed on your computers screen</li>
</ol>
<p>In NERO.</p>
<ol>
<li>Click on <code>SCAN KEY IMAGES</code></li>
<li>Scan the QR code from the computer&rsquo;s screen</li>
<li>Once it has been picked up you can see the <code>Address</code>, <code>Amount</code>, <code>Fee</code> and <code>Total</code>. Click on <code>confirm</code></li>
<li>You should now see the unsigned TX screen.</li>
</ol>
<p>In feather click on <code>Next</code>. Then scan the QR code displayed by NERO to your computer. Once the bar is at 100%, you should again see the <code>Address</code>, <code>Amount</code>, <code>Fee</code> and <code>Total</code>. If your ok with that click on SIGN.</p>
<p>In NERO</p>
<ol>
<li>Click on <code>SCAN SIGNED TX</code></li>
<li>Scan the QR displayed by feather wallet.</li>
<li>Click on <code>Yes</code>, once asked whether or not to broadcast transaction</li>
</ol>
<p>You have now sent the transaction.</p>
<p><strong>if this article helped you out consider <a href="https://4rkal.com/donate">supporting me</a></strong></p>
<div style="text-align: left; margin: 0 auto;">
    <form method="post" action="https://newsletter.4rkal.com/subscription/form" style="background: #2c2c2c; color: #f0f0f0; border-radius: 8px; padding: 15px; max-width: 500px; box-shadow: 0 3px 6px rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.2); font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">
        <div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; gap: 10px;">
            <h3 style="margin: 0; color: #f0f0f0; font-size: 18px;">Subscribe</h3>
            <input type="hidden" name="nonce"/>
            <input type="email" name="email" required placeholder="E-mail" style="width: 100%; padding: 10px; border: 1px solid #666; border-radius: 4px; background: #333; color: #f0f0f0; box-sizing: border-box;"/>
            <div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; gap: 8px;">
                <label style="margin: 0; color: #f0f0f0; display: none;">
                    <input id="78a75" type="checkbox" name="l" checked value="78a75b30-472d-4790-a5d5-7f2ed49662a4" style="accent-color: #fff;"/>
                    Weekly Roundup
                </label>
                <span style="color: #d0d0d0; display: none;">Where I share what I’ve been up to that week, including articles I’ve published, cool finds, tips and tricks, and more!</span>
                <label style="margin: 0; color: #f0f0f0; display: none;">
                    <input id="b3964" type="checkbox" name="l" checked value="b3964560-37b0-43d3-9df9-26589fd6bf8d" style="accent-color: #fff;"/>
                    New Posts
                </label>
                <span style="color: #d0d0d0; display: none;">Receive an email every time I post something new on my blog</span>
            </div>
            <input type="submit" value="Subscribe" style="width: 100%; padding: 10px; border: none; border-radius: 4px; background: #fff; color: #007bff; font-size: 14px; cursor: pointer; transition: background-color 0.3s ease, box-shadow 0.3s ease; box-shadow: 0 1px 3px rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.2);"/>
        </div>
        <p style="text-align: center; margin-top: 10px; color: #d0d0d0; font-size: 10px; margin-bottom:0px;">
            No spam, no ads. Unsubscribe at any time.
        </p>
    </form>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy monero cold storage</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/coldstorage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 18:03:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/coldstorage/</guid>
      <description>In this article I will show you how to &amp;ldquo;easily&amp;rdquo; generate a live archlinux usb with the monero gui pre-installed.
Requirements An archlinux install A usb Setup In this guide I will show you how to build a custom archlinux iso with monerogui installed. I will not be providing any pre-built images.
The first thing you will have to do is install archuseriso. You can install it from the aur using this command:</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In this article I will show you how to &ldquo;easily&rdquo; generate a live archlinux usb with the monero gui pre-installed.</p>
<h2 id="requirements">Requirements</h2>
<ol>
<li>An archlinux install</li>
<li>A usb</li>
</ol>
<h2 id="setup">Setup</h2>
<p>In this guide I will show you how to build a custom archlinux iso with monerogui installed. I will not be providing any pre-built images.</p>
<p>The first thing you will have to do is install <a href="https://github.com/laurent85v/archuseriso">archuseriso</a>. You can install it from the aur using this command:</p>
<p><code>yay -S archuseriso</code></p>
<p>Now open a terminal and navigate to any directory. Then run the following command:</p>
<p><code>sudo aui-mkiso -m 'img' --add-pkg=monero-gui xfce --verbose</code></p>
<p>This will build a new gpt image with persistense, add the monero-gui package and use xfce as the default desktop. The &ndash;verbose flag is optional.</p>
<p>After that is finished building you can use your favourite image writter to write the image. I will be using dd
<code>sudo dd if=out/aui-xfce*.img of=/dev/CHANGEME</code></p>
<p>You will have to write that to your usb, so in /dev/CHANGEME just put your usb. You can find it by running <code>lsblk</code>
<strong>Don&rsquo;t be stupid</strong>
If you enter the wrong device this could lead to data loss. Be careful!</p>
<p>After the image is written you will have to boot to your usb.</p>
<p>First however it is recommended that you disconnect any ethernet/other cables plugged in so that it is trully offline.</p>
<p>You can also <a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=disable+wifi+and+bluetooth+bios">disable wifi and bluetooth from the bios</a> . &ldquo;Advanced&rdquo; users only don&rsquo;t be retarded</p>
<p>Now only plug in your usb drive and reboot into the usb. You will generaly have to press either F8,F9,F10,F11 upon booting and then select your usb.</p>
<p>Now you have two options</p>
<ol>
<li>Boot into persistent.</li>
<li>Boot into memory.</li>
</ol>
<p>When booting into persistent your files will be saved. This however does also involve your wallet file.</p>
<p>For the more secure option you can select boot into memory. This will delete all the traces of the wallet after reboot. You will have to write the seed down and manually enter it upon every boot if you want to authorize transactions.</p>
<p>I will boot into persistent since I will use a strong password and will keep the usb in a safe place. If you want to be extra paranoid use the second option.</p>
<p>After the os has fully booted you will have to click on the <code>Applications</code> icon &gt; internet &gt; <code>Monero GUI</code>. Alternatively open a terminal and type <code>monero-wallet-gui</code></p>
<p>You will now be greated by the monero gui setup guide.</p>
<p>Select your language etc.</p>
<p>Select advanced &gt; Click on <code>Create a new wallet</code> . You can select whatever you want in the wallet name and location &gt; Click next.</p>
<p>Now you will be prompted with your recovery phrase. Write it down on PHYSICAL PAPER and keep it in a safe place. Also note the height and or creation date.</p>
<p>Write it down!
If you don&rsquo;t write down your seed and keep it in a secure place you will lose access to your monero!</p>
<p>Then click next. Now select a strong password. Alteast 12 chars!. Remeber it!</p>
<p>Click next. Then click on <code>Connect to a remote node</code> but don&rsquo;t add one, we don&rsquo;t need it.</p>
<p>Then click on create wallet.</p>
<p>After you have opened your wallet, click on <code>settings</code> and then <code>Create view-only wallet</code>. Then click on ok. Logout of your wallet. Click on <code>Open wallet from file</code> and select the new file called WALLETNAME_viewonly.</p>
<p>Once you have logged into your view only wallet click on settings again and select <code>Show seeds and keys</code>. Scroll down to the botton and import your view only wallet via qr to your mobile wallet. Here are some guides for every wallet:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://guides.cakewallet.com/docs/basic-features/restore-wallet-from-qr-code/">Cake wallet</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.monerujo.io/resources/monerujo_manual.html">Monerujo</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="what-have-we-acomplished">What have we acomplished?</h2>
<p>You now have a cold wallet for offline signing on your usb and a view-only wallet on your phone. Basicly you can view all incoming transactions on your phone but can&rsquo;t spend them there. Only your computer booted into the usb can sign them.</p>
<h2 id="signing-transactions">Signing transactions</h2>
<p>I won&rsquo;t cover doing this in this article. But you can find out more about how to send transactions from cold storage <a href="https://monerodocs.org/cold-storage/offline-transaction-signing/">here</a></p>
<div style="text-align: left; margin: 0 auto;">
    <form method="post" action="https://newsletter.4rkal.com/subscription/form" style="background: #2c2c2c; color: #f0f0f0; border-radius: 8px; padding: 15px; max-width: 500px; box-shadow: 0 3px 6px rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.2); font-family: Arial, sans-serif;">
        <div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; gap: 10px;">
            <h3 style="margin: 0; color: #f0f0f0; font-size: 18px;">Subscribe</h3>
            <input type="hidden" name="nonce"/>
            <input type="email" name="email" required placeholder="E-mail" style="width: 100%; padding: 10px; border: 1px solid #666; border-radius: 4px; background: #333; color: #f0f0f0; box-sizing: border-box;"/>
            <div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; gap: 8px;">
                <label style="margin: 0; color: #f0f0f0; display: none;">
                    <input id="78a75" type="checkbox" name="l" checked value="78a75b30-472d-4790-a5d5-7f2ed49662a4" style="accent-color: #fff;"/>
                    Weekly Roundup
                </label>
                <span style="color: #d0d0d0; display: none;">Where I share what I’ve been up to that week, including articles I’ve published, cool finds, tips and tricks, and more!</span>
                <label style="margin: 0; color: #f0f0f0; display: none;">
                    <input id="b3964" type="checkbox" name="l" checked value="b3964560-37b0-43d3-9df9-26589fd6bf8d" style="accent-color: #fff;"/>
                    New Posts
                </label>
                <span style="color: #d0d0d0; display: none;">Receive an email every time I post something new on my blog</span>
            </div>
            <input type="submit" value="Subscribe" style="width: 100%; padding: 10px; border: none; border-radius: 4px; background: #fff; color: #007bff; font-size: 14px; cursor: pointer; transition: background-color 0.3s ease, box-shadow 0.3s ease; box-shadow: 0 1px 3px rgba(0, 0, 0, 0.2);"/>
        </div>
        <p style="text-align: center; margin-top: 10px; color: #d0d0d0; font-size: 10px; margin-bottom:0px;">
            No spam, no ads. Unsubscribe at any time.
        </p>
    </form>
</div>]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Monero is the ultimate form of a cryptocurrency</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/whymonero/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 20:23:16 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/whymonero/</guid>
      <description>In this article, I will tell you why Monero fits my views of what a cryptocurrency should look like.
What is Monero? Monero is a decentralized cryptocurrency. It uses a public distributed ledger with privacy-enhancing technologies that obfuscate transactions to achieve anonymity and fungibility. Observers cannot decipher addresses trading Monero, transaction amounts, address balances, or transaction histories.
Monero works like any other currency but with some privacy and decentralization innovations.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In this article, I will tell you why Monero fits my views of what a cryptocurrency should look like.</p>
<h1 id="what-is-monero">What is Monero?</h1>
<p>Monero is a decentralized cryptocurrency. It uses a public distributed ledger with privacy-enhancing technologies that obfuscate transactions to achieve anonymity and fungibility. Observers cannot decipher addresses trading Monero, transaction amounts, address balances, or transaction histories.</p>
<p>Monero works like any other currency but with some privacy and decentralization innovations.</p>
<p>Monero uses <a href="https://www.investopedia.com/terms/s/stealth-address-cryptocurrency.asp">stealth addresses</a> alongside <a href="https://web.getmonero.org/resources/moneropedia/ringsignatures.html">ring signatures</a> and <a href="https://www.getmonero.org/resources/moneropedia/ringCT.html">ring CTs</a> to &ldquo;hide&rdquo; the transaction and transaction amounts, enhancing transaction privacy. To further decentralize the network, Monero uses the <a href="https://www.getmonero.org/resources/moneropedia/randomx.html">RandomX algorithm</a> to discourage the use of ASICs.</p>
<h1 id="the-main-problems-with-bitcoin-and-other-cryptos">The Main Problems with Bitcoin and Other Cryptos</h1>
<p>Bitcoin may seem like a perfect currency. However, under the hood, Bitcoin has many flaws.</p>
<p>One of the main problems with Bitcoin is that it isn&rsquo;t actually censorship-resistant. A central bank or government can blacklist your address and block exchanges from accepting it. While there are ways to get around that, it isn&rsquo;t easy. Monero, on the other hand, is censorship-resistant as it doesn&rsquo;t display transaction amounts or receivers.</p>
<p>Another problem with Bitcoin and other PoW currencies is that they are actually controlled by a small number of people since they are really hard to mine, among many other factors. Monero is a relatively easy currency to mine and is ASIC-resistant, which makes it even more decentralized as anyone with a computer and an internet connection can start contributing to the network.</p>
<p>Bitcoin has a block size limit, which results in more expensive transactions and longer waiting times. Monero uses a <a href="https://localmonero.co/knowledge/dynamic-block-size">dynamic block size</a>.</p>
<p>Also, Bitcoin has a <a href="https://bitinfocharts.com/comparison/bitcoin-confirmationtime.html#3m">high block time</a>, which means that transactions take longer to be confirmed and executed. Bitcoin&rsquo;s block time is ~10 minutes, while <a href="https://bitinfocharts.com/comparison/monero-confirmationtime.html#3y">Monero&rsquo;s block time</a> is ~2 minutes.</p>
<p>Bitcoin has halving once every 4 years. The halving halves the amount of mined (printed) Bitcoin in every block. This, by itself, increases price volatility and transaction fee volatility.</p>
<p>Monero has chosen a 0.6 XMR block reward forever. Any good currency wants to have as little volatility as possible. Monero is a currency, not a &ldquo;number go up coin.&rdquo;</p>
<h1 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h1>
<p>Monero is basically what people think Bitcoin is. Here&rsquo;s a great <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ak5TFr26BaE">video about it</a>.</p>
<h1 id="disclaimer">Disclaimer</h1>
<p>Tech has nothing to do with price. This article reviews the tech of this project and is thus not financial advice. Please DYOR when investing.</p>
<h1 id="support-me">Support Me</h1>
<p>If you enjoyed this article, consider supporting me:</p>
<p>Monero:</p>
<p><code>8AztDJtwb7iKaqP4KXRG39VibAacCY1mMfH3bNsVjhYMYbohtT5LKoTSRP6vJGtjeBSPEpFdHZx3ZL3iVowYdkqeQwPAG2o</code></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
