<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Automation on 4rkal</title>
    <link>https://4rkal.com/tags/automation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Automation on 4rkal</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 11:19:17 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://4rkal.com/tags/automation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to setup a selfhosted newsletter using listmonk</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/listmonk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 11:19:17 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/listmonk/</guid>
      <description>What is listmonk? Listmonk is a selfhosted newsletter and mailing list manager. It is free and opensource, so you have full control over your data. It also offers a super clean webui:&#xA;Why choose listmonk over mailchimp, buttodown etc For me, running a newsletter means owning my email list.&#xA;When people create newsletters they want to break free from the big platforms like Twitter or YouTube. When you use a proprietary service like Mailchimp, you’re still tied down to their rules and limitations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automating your web browser with selenium</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/selenium/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 21:23:38 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/selenium/</guid>
      <description>Selenium is a very good skill to have as you can automate almost everything that you can do with a web browser.&#xA;In this tutorial, we’ll learn how to use Python and Selenium to automate a web browser. This is an updated version of my previous article which unfortunately doesn&amp;rsquo;t work anymore. If you’re a complete beginner, read my python article to understand the basics. (https://4rkal.com/posts/python/)&#xA;What is selenium? Selenium is an open source umbrella project for a range of tools and libraries aimed at supporting browser automation.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
