<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>4rkal</title>
    <link>https://4rkal.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on 4rkal</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 17:33:38 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://4rkal.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 19:29:56 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi there 👋 I’m 4rkal. I created this blog as free alternative to my medium&#xA;I usually post about interesting topics I stumble upon, particularly in areas like Linux, Privacy, Crypto, and Programming.&#xA;If you enjoy my content, consider supporting me with a donation.&#xA;Current Projects Here’s what I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on:&#xA;This Blog - Continuously updating with new content. CypherGoat- A cryptocurrency instant swap aggregator. Videiro - Free video editor portfolio platform Videiro Recruitment - Video editor requirement website.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>If Linux is so great why isn&#39;t everyone using it?</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 17:33:38 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/linux/</guid>
      <description>What even is Linux? Linux is a family of free and open source operating systems based on the Linux kernel.&#xA;Although being completely free (unlike alternatives) Linux currently only has 4.5% of the global desktop operating system market, a very low percentage.&#xA;What makes Linux great? The core difference between Linux and other mainstream desktop operating systems (windows, macOS) is the fact that it is free and open source. This allows it to be:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to build a URL shortener in Go</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/url-shortener-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 18:24:11 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/url-shortener-go/</guid>
      <description>In this article I will be going through how to make a url shortener in go. The final result will look something like this shortr, source code&#xA;This is a great weekend project especially if you&amp;rsquo;re new to go.&#xA;What is a url shortener? A URL shortener is a tool that takes a long URL and shrinks it down into something much shorter and easier to share. Instead of copying and pasting a long string of letters, numbers, and symbols, you get a compact version that leads to the same destination.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to deploy django to production</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/django-prod/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 11:54:29 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/django-prod/</guid>
      <description>I recently deployed my very own django application to production. The website is called videiro.com and was developed in django + HTML/CSS/JS + Tailwind.&#xA;Setup I am using a debian 12 server which will expose my application via cloudflare tunnels. All of the static files are being served via nginx and the Django project is being ran by gunicorn.&#xA;In this guide I will show you how I set this up.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Newsletter</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/newsletter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 11:11:15 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/newsletter/</guid>
      <description>Join my weekly roundup, where I’ll share what I’ve been up to that week, including articles I’ve published, cool finds, tips and tricks and more!&#xA;Subscribe Weekly Roundup </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to setup a selfhosted newsletter using listmonk</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/listmonk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 11:19:17 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/listmonk/</guid>
      <description>What is listmonk? Listmonk is a selfhosted newsletter and mailing list manager. It is free and opensource, so you have full control over your data. It also offers a super clean webui:&#xA;Why choose listmonk over mailchimp, buttodown etc For me, running a newsletter means owning my email list.&#xA;When people create newsletters they want to break free from the big platforms like Twitter or YouTube. When you use a proprietary service like Mailchimp, you’re still tied down to their rules and limitations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selfhost your own gitea instance - selfhosted, lightweight github alternative</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/gitea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 19:21:15 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/gitea/</guid>
      <description>In this article I&amp;rsquo;ll walk you through how you can run your own gitea instance. But first&#xA;What is gitea? Gitea is a painless selfhosted Git service. It is written in Go and is extremely lightweight. I run a gitea instance on my Le Potato and it barely uses any resources.&#xA;Why use gitea (vs GitHub, GitLab etc) I started running my own Gitea instance because I wanted a private place to host my Obsidian notes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Improve Go API request performance</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/goapi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 12:25:15 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/goapi/</guid>
      <description>The project I recently started working on a cryptocurrency exchange aggregator. Basically I send out requests to a bunch of different exchanges and compare rates. This has to be made as fast as possible. In this post, I’ll some show some tweaks that I made in order to boost my performance significantly.&#xA;However keep in mind that I am not an expert (especially in go) and I am just sharing my findings from my own personal project.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Domain</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/updates/newdomain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 16:41:25 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/updates/newdomain/</guid>
      <description>As part of the New Look, new start. I have decided to purchase this amazing domain (4rkal.com).&#xA;As of today migration has been successful. All links should be redirecting to this domain.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Obsidian &#43; Hugo blogging setup</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/obsidianhugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 17:15:57 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/obsidianhugo/</guid>
      <description>If you clicked on this article you probably know what Obsidian and Hugo are but if you don&amp;rsquo;t here&amp;rsquo;s a quick explanation:&#xA;Obsidian Obsidian is a feature packed markdown editor. But it&amp;rsquo;s not just a markdown editor. It&amp;rsquo;s a way to manage knowledge. It&amp;rsquo;s great for organizing your thoughts in a flexible, non-linear way.&#xA;Obsidian works on all platforms. So you can write articles from basically any platform.&#xA;I have been taking all of my notes in it for a couple of months now and it&amp;rsquo;s amazing!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New look, new start</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/newlook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 16:17:31 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/newlook/</guid>
      <description>I recently switched from the hugo LoveIt theme to PaperModX . Why the switch? The LoveIt theme hasn&amp;rsquo;t been updated in 2+ years. PaperModX has a more modern look LoveIt doesn&amp;rsquo;t work that well with obsidian. The overall switch went pretty smoothly. You can see the changes I made in this commit.&#xA;For anyone wondering this what the website used to look like&#xA;More articles to come! The theme wasn&amp;rsquo;t the only change that I made.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultimate Monero ColdStorage Guide (Feather X Anonero)</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/feathernero/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 21:00:30 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/feathernero/</guid>
      <description>In this comprehensive guide, I will walk you through the process of easily setting up Monero cold storage using an old computer and your smartphone, using animated QR codes. No USB needed!&#xA;Requirements An old laptop/computer with a webcam (to be kept offline). Called offline or cold computer. An android smartphone. Your main computer Required reads Before starting this article you must read:&#xA;Key concepts Monero offline transaction signing details Cold computer setup Your offline computer/laptop will be signing all of the transactions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Easy monero cold storage</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/coldstorage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 18:03:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/coldstorage/</guid>
      <description>In this article I will show you how to &amp;ldquo;easily&amp;rdquo; generate a live archlinux usb with the monero gui pre-installed.&#xA;Requirements An archlinux install A usb Setup In this guide I will show you how to build a custom archlinux iso with monerogui installed. I will not be providing any pre-built images.&#xA;The first thing you will have to do is install archuseriso. You can install it from the aur using this command:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Created the monero archive</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/updates/monero-archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 21:34:20 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/updates/monero-archive/</guid>
      <description>Created the monero archive (tor)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hacktoberfest 2023</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/updates/hacktoberfest23/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 21:30:30 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/updates/hacktoberfest23/</guid>
      <description>I am participating in hacktoberfest 2023&#xA;Got a tree planted in my name here</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SSH Remote Access NO Port-Forwarding NO Cloudflare</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/onionssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 19:17:04 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/onionssh/</guid>
      <description>In this article I will show you how I securely connect to my remote machines without having to configure port forwarding.&#xA;Requirements: A computer &amp;ldquo;server&amp;rdquo; (running linux) A internet connection Another computer to connect to your server (running linux) Why? If you want to access your server without portforwarding in a extremely secure fashion you will want to follow this tutorial. You will be connecting to the server via tor which will make it harder for anyone to find the url of the server and ill show you how to setup keybased auth for even more security!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I setup this blog for free (domain, hosting, ssl) Complete Guide</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/thisblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 18:13:03 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/thisblog/</guid>
      <description>In this article I’ll show you how I setup this blog completely for free. I’ll show you how to use hugo to write your blog, Cloudflare and eu.org for your domain and ssl, Render and github for the hosting and even how to get your blog on google.&#xA;What is hugo? Hugo is a fast and popular open-source static site generator used for creating static websites without requiring a database or dynamic components.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python for Complete Beginners</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 20:52:42 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/python/</guid>
      <description>Why you should use Python. Going over the basics of Python.&#xA;In this course/article I will be talking about why someone should use Python. Later on, I will be tackling the basics of Python. But let&amp;rsquo;s start by explaining what coding is.&#xA;What is coding? Coding means writing instructions for computers and a finished set of instructions is known as a program. Computer programs control everything from smartphones to space rockets.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PocketBase self-hosted Firebase alternative</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/pocketbase/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 20:44:46 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/pocketbase/</guid>
      <description>What is PocketBase PocketBase is an open source backend made in go consisting of embedded database (SQLite) with realtime subscriptions, built-in auth management, convenient dashboard UI and simple REST-ish API.&#xA;Install PocketBase The first thing that you will have to do is head to https://pocketbase.io and select the file for your operating system. Since I am using linux I will show how to set this up on linux but it should be pretty similar for any other os.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Monero is the ultimate form of a cryptocurrency</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/whymonero/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 20:23:16 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/whymonero/</guid>
      <description>In this article, I will tell you why Monero fits my views of what a cryptocurrency should look like.&#xA;What is Monero? Monero is a decentralized cryptocurrency. It uses a public distributed ledger with privacy-enhancing technologies that obfuscate transactions to achieve anonymity and fungibility. Observers cannot decipher addresses trading Monero, transaction amounts, address balances, or transaction histories.&#xA;Monero works like any other currency but with some privacy and decentralization innovations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Create a MultiBoot USB using ventoy</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/ventoy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 20:11:51 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/ventoy/</guid>
      <description>With ventoy, you don’t need to format the disk over and over, you just need to copy the ISO files to the USB drive and boot them directly.&#xA;Whats ventoy? Ventoy is a free and open-source utility used for writing image files such as .iso, .wim, .img, .vhd(x), and .efi files onto storage media to create bootable USB flash drives. Once Ventoy is installed onto a USB drive, there is no need to reformat the disk to update it with new installation files; it is enough to copy the .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nmap(Network Mapper) For Beginners</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/nmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 17:37:03 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/nmap/</guid>
      <description>Whether you want to scan your network for vulnerabilities or just want to see which ports you have open, nmap can be extremely useful.&#xA;What is nmap Nmap (Network Mapper) is a network scanner created by Gordon Lyon . Nmap sends packets and examines the answers to find hosts and services on a computer network. For probing computer networks, Nmap offers a variety of functionalities, including host discovery, service detection, and operating system detection.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Microsoft is monetizing the GitHub code base</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/githubmon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 17:21:56 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/githubmon/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft purchased GitHub in 2018, something many users are not aware of. After Microsoft’s acquisition of GitHub there have been many controversies like blocking private repositories and access to GitHub pages in certain countries and of course, GitHub Copilot.&#xA;What is Github Copilot GitHub Copilot is an artificial intelligence tool developed by GitHub and OpenAI to assist users of Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio, Neovim, and JetBrains integrated development environments (IDEs) by autocompleting code.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Set Up Your Own Git Server: A Simple Guide</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/git/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 17:11:40 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/git/</guid>
      <description>Thinking about setting up your own Git server? There are plenty of perks to doing so instead of relying on platforms like GitHub. For starters, you&amp;rsquo;ll have complete control over your code, ensuring it can’t be used for profit or deleted by anyone but you.&#xA;What You’ll Need A Computer for Your Server: Ideally running Linux (Debian is a solid choice). Internet Connection: Pretty essential for accessing your server remotely. Another Computer with Git Installed: This is what you&amp;rsquo;ll use to interact with your server.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Host your own private search engine — searX</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/searx/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 23:21:53 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/searx/</guid>
      <description>We rely on google more and more, but it’s interesting to know how much data Google is now handling. Alphabet aka Google describes its extensive data collection practices in its privacy policy. The company stores an astounding quantity of data. An estimated 15 exabytes of YOUR data are stored by Google. Google is tracking your every move.&#xA;What is searX? Searx is a free and open-source metasearch engine, available under the GNU Affero General Public License version 3, with the aim of protecting the privacy of its users.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Become anonymous and somewhat untraceable with tails os</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/tails/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 23:03:40 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/tails/</guid>
      <description>In this article we will talk about what tails is and how to install and more.&#xA;What is tails? Tails, or The Amnesic Incognito Live System, is a security-focused Debian-based Linux distribution aimed at preserving privacy and anonymity.It connects to the Internet exclusively through the anonymity network Tor. The system is designed to be booted as a live DVD or live USB, and leaves no digital footprint on the machine unless explicitly told to do so.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donate</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/donate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 20:29:31 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/donate/</guid>
      <description>Support My Work If you enjoy my articles, consider supporting me through any of the following methods:&#xA;Crypto Donations Monero (XMR): 8AztDJtwb7iKaqP4KXRG39VibAacCY1mMfH4bNsVjhYMYbohtT5LKoTSRP6vJGtjeBSPEpFdHZx3ZL3iVowYdkqeQwPAG2 Altcoins: Donate 250+ altcoins via Trocador:&#xA;Clearnet Tor Other Methods LiberaPay: Buy Me a Coffee: </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Get ad free web with Pi-hole</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/pihole/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 21:17:13 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/pihole/</guid>
      <description>In this article, I will show you how to set up Pi-hole. Pi-hole will allow you to block in-app ads, improve your network&amp;rsquo;s performance, and monitor statistics. Pi-hole also allows you to create a VPN.&#xA;What is Pi-hole? Pi-hole is a Linux network-level advertisement and Internet tracker blocking application that acts as a DNS sinkhole and optionally a DHCP server, intended for use on a private network. It is designed for low-power embedded devices with network capability, such as the Raspberry Pi, but can be installed on any Linux machine.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Securing ssh with Key-Based authentication</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/sssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 21:08:47 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/sssh/</guid>
      <description>SSH keys provide an extremely secure way of logging into your server.&#xA;SSH Password Based VS Key Based Authentication Clients can be authenticated by an SSH server in a variety of ways. The most basic is password authentication, which is simple to use but not particularly secure. The more advanced and secure way is via ssh keys.Brute-forcing a password-protected account is quite possible thanks to modern computing power and automated scripts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setup a tor website (hidden service)</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/torhs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 20:56:02 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/torhs/</guid>
      <description>In this article i will be showing you how to host your “dark web” aka Tor website for free.&#xA;What is Tor? Tor — short for the Onion Routing project — is an open-source privacy network that enables anonymous web browsing. The worldwide Tor computer network uses secure, encrypted protocols to ensure that users’ online privacy is protected. Tor users’ digital data and communications are shielded using a layered approach that resembles the nested layers of an onion.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The importance of open source software</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/opensource/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 20:43:23 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/opensource/</guid>
      <description>As the linuxfoundation states about 95% of cloud providers run kubernetes which is an open sourced solution, the Apache Web server powers millions of websites including netflix.com, spotify.com and more. Most of the Internets core functions are based on open source technology. But what is it and why is it so important?&#xA;What is open sourced software? Open-source software is computer software that is distributed under a license that allows users to use, study, modify and distribute the program and its source code to anyone and for any purpose.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self host your own website</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/shwebsite/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 20:23:16 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/shwebsite/</guid>
      <description>In this article i will show you how to self host your own website securely.&#xA;Requirements A computer or microcomputer to host the website The computer needs to run linux An internet connection (Its pretty hard without one, trust me) Lets get started!&#xA;Installation The first thing that we will have to do is setup our nginx site.&#xA;We first have to be root&#xA;sudo su&#xA;If you dont have sudo installed try:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry pi security camera</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/rpicamera/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 20:03:25 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/rpicamera/</guid>
      <description>In this article i will show you how to setup a raspberry pi security camera using motion. In the end of this article you will have a fully functioning security camera with a live feed and motion detection.&#xA;Requirements Raspberry pi or any other computer Web cam Any kind of debian based distro installed on the pi/computer Setup In this article we will be using the motion package (https://motion-project.github.io/)&#xA;To get started power on your raspberry pi and ssh into the machine or just connect it to a monitor and a keyboard.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How SSH works</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/howsshworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2023 19:36:25 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/howsshworks/</guid>
      <description>If you work in the IT industry, you’ve undoubtedly heard of ssh. But how does it work?&#xA;SSH (secure shell) is a network protocol that allows two computers to connect securely over the internet. SSH uses encryption to prevent hackers from reading data sent between two connected devices.&#xA;SSH is divided into three layers:&#xA;The transport layer The connection layer The authentication layer During and after authentication, the transport layer establishes safe and secure communication between a client and a server.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automating your web browser with selenium</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/selenium/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 21:23:38 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/selenium/</guid>
      <description>Selenium is a very good skill to have as you can automate almost everything that you can do with a web browser.&#xA;In this tutorial, we’ll learn how to use Python and Selenium to automate a web browser. This is an updated version of my previous article which unfortunately doesn&amp;rsquo;t work anymore. If you’re a complete beginner, read my python article to understand the basics. (https://4rkal.com/posts/python/)&#xA;What is selenium? Selenium is an open source umbrella project for a range of tools and libraries aimed at supporting browser automation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why computers can’t represent 0.3 accurately</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/zeropointthree/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 19:27:44 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/zeropointthree/</guid>
      <description>Most people know that adding up 0.1 + 0.2 equals 0.3. However computers represent it as 0.30000000000000004 .&#xA;Here is a screenshot of it in python3 Your first thought might be that this is just some kind of error. Well its not&#xA;Why does this happen? Fractions can be represented precisely in the base 10 system (used by humans) if a prime factor of the base is used (10).&#xA;2 and 5 are the prime factors of 10.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Search</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/search/</guid>
      <description>search</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
