<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>privacy on 4rkal&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://4rkal.com/tags/privacy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in privacy on 4rkal&#39;s blog</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://4rkal.com/4rkal.png</url>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/4rkal.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 20:44:46 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://4rkal.com/tags/privacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PocketBase self-hosted Firebase alternative</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/pocketbase/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 20:44:46 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/pocketbase/</guid>
      <description>What is PocketBase PocketBase is an open source backend made in go consisting of embedded database (SQLite) with realtime subscriptions, built-in auth management, convenient dashboard UI and simple REST-ish API.
Install PocketBase The first thing that you will have to do is head to https://pocketbase.io and select the file for your operating system. Since I am using linux I will show how to set this up on linux but it should be pretty similar for any other os.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="what-is-pocketbase">What is PocketBase</h1>
<p>PocketBase is an open source backend made in go consisting of embedded database (SQLite) with realtime subscriptions, built-in auth management, convenient dashboard UI and simple REST-ish API.</p>
<h1 id="install-pocketbase">Install PocketBase</h1>
<p>The first thing that you will have to do is head to <a href="https://pocketbase.io">https://pocketbase.io</a> and select the file for your operating system. Since I am using linux I will show how to set this up on linux but it should be pretty similar for any other os.</p>
<p>Unzip the file and open up a terminal to the path that you extracted the file to and type:</p>
<p><code>./pocketbase serve</code></p>
<p>If you want to serve some static content you can create a new directory called pb_public</p>
<p><code>mkdir pb_public</code></p>
<p>Then paste any content into that directory</p>
<p>eg.</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>&lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt;
&lt;html lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;
&lt;head&gt;
    &lt;meta charset=&#34;UTF-8&#34;&gt;
    &lt;meta http-equiv=&#34;X-UA-Compatible&#34; content=&#34;IE=edge&#34;&gt;
    &lt;meta name=&#34;viewport&#34; content=&#34;width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0&#34;&gt;
    &lt;title&gt;Epic Website&lt;/title&gt;
&lt;/head&gt;
&lt;body&gt;
    &lt;h1&gt;My epic website&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;
</code></pre><p>And save that as index.html inside of the pb_public folder</p>
<p>Now if you head to http://127.0.0.1:8090/ you should see the website that we entered above.</p>
<p>If you go to http://127.0.0.1:8090/_/ it will take you to an admin portal. There you should create a account. After you have setted up your account you should see something like this.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/../assets/pocketbase.webp" type="" alt="1"  /></p>
<p>Here you can add and create users</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/../assets/pocketbase2.webp" type="" alt="2"  /></p>
<p>And also create custom collections eg</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/../assets/pocketbase3.webp" type="" alt="2"  /></p>
<p>If you click on the settings icon you can see that you will be able to add applications, mail settings, file storage (s3) , export/import collections, add or remove auth providers, token options and add/remove admins.</p>
<p>That’s it for now if you want to learn more check out <a href="https://pocketbase.io/docs/">https://pocketbase.io/docs/</a></p>
<p><em><strong>If you enjoyed this article consider <a href="../../donate">supporting me</a></strong></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Microsoft is monetizing the GitHub code base</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/githubmon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 17:21:56 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/githubmon/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft purchased GitHub in 2018, something many users are not aware of. After Microsoft’s acquisition of GitHub there have been many controversies like blocking private repositories and access to GitHub pages in certain countries and of course, GitHub Copilot.
What is Github Copilot GitHub Copilot is an artificial intelligence tool developed by GitHub and OpenAI to assist users of Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio, Neovim, and JetBrains integrated development environments (IDEs) by autocompleting code.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Microsoft purchased GitHub in 2018, something many users are not aware of. After Microsoft’s acquisition of GitHub there have been many controversies like blocking private repositories and access to GitHub pages in certain countries and of course, GitHub Copilot.</p>
<h1 id="what-is-github-copilot">What is Github Copilot</h1>
<p>GitHub Copilot is an artificial intelligence tool developed by GitHub and OpenAI to assist users of Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio, Neovim, and JetBrains integrated development environments (IDEs) by autocompleting code. Currently available by subscription to individual developers, the tool was first announced by GitHub on 29 June 2021, and works best for users coding in Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, Ruby, and Go.</p>
<h1 id="how-does-copilot-work">How does copilot work?</h1>
<p>GitHub Copilot is powered by the OpenAI Codex, an artificial intelligence model created by OpenAI. The Generative Pre-trained Transformer 3 (GPT-3) language model, which uses deep learning to create text that resembles human speech, is improved and used in production as the OpenAI Codex.</p>
<p>Github copilot was trained on a selection of the English language, public GitHub repositories, including 59 gigabytes of Python code sourced from 54 million public GitHub repositories.</p>
<p>There still is a lot of controversy about whether GitHub should be allowed to do so, as most open source licences obviously don’t contain anything against analyzing your code with AI and selling it. Also, as AI is analyzing the code base it is not classified as derivative work which seems to be legal. However, it seems quite unethical by Microsoft as Copilot is a paid service that relies on analyzing other people’s code.
Read more:
<a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/7/22561180/github-copilot-legal-copyright-fair-use-public-code">https://www.theverge.com/2021/7/7/22561180/github-copilot-legal-copyright-fair-use-public-code</a></p>
<p>If copilot was free to use it would make a lot more sense as it utilizes FOSS(Free and open sourced software) in order to work. However with Microsoft’s decision to make copilot payed they are monetizing most off GitHub&rsquo;s code base which is an illegal grey zone.</p>
<p>Analyzing a huge amount of code without any security features has led to many problems like GitHub leaking phone numbers (I even encountered it while testing copilot out).</p>
<p><a href="https://github.com/community/community/discussions/9584?sort=top?sort=top">https://github.com/community/community/discussions/9584?sort=top?sort=top</a></p>
<p>Last but not least by using GitHub copilot you agree to the ToS which clearly states</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>GitHub Copilot gives you certain choices about how it uses the data it collects. User engagement data, including pseudonymous identifiers and general usage data, is required for the use of GitHub Copilot and will continue to be collected, processed, and shared with Microsoft and OpenAI as you use GitHub Copilot. You can choose whether your code snippets are collected and retained by GitHub and further processed and shared with Microsoft and OpenAI by adjusting your user settings.
</code></pre><h1 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h1>
<p>I personally don’t use or will ever use GitHub Copilot or recommend it to anyone for the following reasons:</p>
<ol>
<li>Doesn&rsquo;t help you learn. Instead does the opposite.</li>
<li>Recommends other peoples’ phone numbers, emails and even aws keys. No features have been implemented to stop this as far as I know.</li>
<li>Tracks your usage and collects a lot of data. Like Source code that you are editing, related files and other files open in the same IDE or editor, URLs of repositories and files paths.</li>
<li>Is paid and proprietary. (You pay to be tracked)</li>
<li>Monetizes Open Source Software in an unethical way.</li>
<li><a href="https://cyber.nyu.edu/2021/10/15/ccs-researchers-find-github-copilot-generates-vulnerable-code-40-of-the-time/">Github CoPilot generates vulnerable code 40% of the time</a></li>
</ol>
<p>PS if you don’t want GitHub to legally index your code, you could try one of these <a href="https://github.com/big-tech-sux/resistant-licenses">licenses</a> They might work</p>
<p>***If you enjoyed this article consider <a href="https://4rkal.com/donate">supporting me</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Host your own private search engine — searX</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/searx/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 23:21:53 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/searx/</guid>
      <description>We rely on google more and more, but it’s interesting to know how much data Google is now handling. Alphabet aka Google describes its extensive data collection practices in its privacy policy. The company stores an astounding quantity of data. An estimated 15 exabytes of YOUR data are stored by Google. Google is tracking your every move.
What is searX? Searx is a free and open-source metasearch engine, available under the GNU Affero General Public License version 3, with the aim of protecting the privacy of its users.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We rely on google more and more, but it’s interesting to know how much data Google is now handling. Alphabet aka Google describes its extensive data collection practices in its privacy policy. The company stores an astounding quantity of data. An estimated 15 exabytes of YOUR data are stored by Google. Google is tracking your every move.</p>
<h1 id="what-is-searx">What is searX?</h1>
<p>Searx is a free and open-source metasearch engine, available under the GNU Affero General Public License version 3, with the aim of protecting the privacy of its users. In order to do this, Searx does not provide the search engines from which it receives results with users’ IP addresses or search histories. Tracking cookies served by the search engines are blocked, preventing user-profiling-based results modification.</p>
<p>Users can run private instances of Searx on their own computer, but there are also many public, user-run, Searx instances.</p>
<p>In this article i will show you how to run your own searX instance.</p>
<h1 id="what-is-a-metasearch-engine">What is a metasearch engine?</h1>
<p>A web search engine’s data is used by a metasearch engine, an online information retrieval tool, to create its own results. Metasearch engines automatically query search engines eg Google after receiving user input. The users are shown sufficient data that has been gathered, sorted, and presented.</p>
<h1 id="requirements">Requirements</h1>
<ol>
<li>An computer (preferably running linux). Check out my article on how to install linux here <a href="https://4rkal.medium.com/install-a-debian-server-54add9133eec">https://4rkal.medium.com/install-a-debian-server-54add9133eec</a></li>
<li>an internet connection</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="installing-on-windows">Installing on windows</h1>
<p>To install on windows you will have to install wsl and follow the setup guide for linux bellow</p>
<p>To see how to install wsl head to <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/wsl/install">https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/wsl/install</a></p>
<h1 id="installing-on-linux-debian">Installing on Linux (debian)</h1>
<p>First update your system
<code>sudo apt-get update &amp;&amp; sudo apt-get upgrade</code>
Now install required packages
<code>sudo apt install -y python3-dev python3-babel python3-venv uwsgi uwsgi-plugin-python3 git build-essential libxslt-dev zlib1g-dev libffi-dev libssl-dev </code>
Now you will have to create a new user called searx</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>sudo -H useradd --shell /bin/bash --system \
    --home-dir &#34;/usr/local/searx&#34; \
    --comment &#39;Privacy-respecting metasearch engine&#39; searx

sudo -H mkdir &#34;/usr/local/searx&#34;
sudo -H chown -R &#34;searx:searx&#34; &#34;/usr/local/searx&#34;
</code></pre><p>Now change user to searx</p>
<p><code>git clone &quot;https://github.com/searx/searx.git&quot; &quot;/usr/local/searx/searx-src&quot;t</code></p>
<p>Now create a virtual environment</p>
<p><code>echo &quot;. /usr/local/searx/searx-pyenv/bin/activate&quot; &gt;&gt;  &quot;/usr/local/searx/.profile&quot;</code></p>
<p>To install searx’s dependencies, exit the searx bash session you opened above and restart a new. Before install, first check if your virtualenv was sourced from the login (~/.profile):</p>
<p>Update dependencies</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>pip install -U pip
pip install -U setuptools
pip install -U wheel
pip install -U pyyaml
</code></pre><p>Jump to searx’s working tree and install searx into virtualenv</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>cd &#34;/usr/local/searx/searx-src&#34;
pip install -e .
</code></pre><p>Now go back to your default user</p>
<p><code>exit</code></p>
<p>And type
<code>sudo -H mkdir -p &quot;/etc/searx&quot;</code></p>
<p>Then</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>sudo -H cp &#34;/usr/local/searx/searx-src/utils/templates/etc/searx/use_default_settings.yml&#34; \
             &#34;/etc/searx/settings.yml&#34;
</code></pre><p>Now you can edit your settings file</p>
<p><code>sudo nano /etc/searx/settings.yml</code></p>
<p>You can change the secret_key</p>
<p>I will change the port and bind_address but you can change whatever you want.</p>
<p>Now log back in to your searx user</p>
<p><code>sudo -H -u searx -i</code></p>
<p>Change directory</p>
<p><code>cd /usr/local/searx/searx-src</code></p>
<p>Export the settings path</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>export 
SEARX_SETTINGS_PATH=&#34;/etc/searx/settings.yml&#34;
</code></pre><p>Finally run the web app
<code>python searx/webapp.py</code>
Now if you head to 127.0.0.1:8888 you should be able to see something like this
<img loading="lazy" src="/../assets/searx.webp" type="" alt="1"  />
<strong>GG</strong> you did it enjoy privacy (in search engines)</p>
<p>*<strong>If you enjoyed this article consider <a href="../../donate">supporting me</a></strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Become anonymous and somewhat untraceable with tails os</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/tails/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 23:03:40 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/tails/</guid>
      <description>In this article we will talk about what tails is and how to install and more.
What is tails? Tails, or The Amnesic Incognito Live System, is a security-focused Debian-based Linux distribution aimed at preserving privacy and anonymity.It connects to the Internet exclusively through the anonymity network Tor. The system is designed to be booted as a live DVD or live USB, and leaves no digital footprint on the machine unless explicitly told to do so.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In this article we will talk about what tails is and how to install and more.</p>
<h1 id="what-is-tails">What is tails?</h1>
<p>Tails, or The Amnesic Incognito Live System, is a security-focused Debian-based Linux distribution aimed at preserving privacy and anonymity.It connects to the Internet exclusively through the anonymity network Tor. The system is designed to be booted as a live DVD or live USB, and leaves no digital footprint on the machine unless explicitly told to do so.</p>
<h1 id="what-is-the-tor-network">What is the tor network?</h1>
<p>Tor, short for The Onion Router, is free and open-source software for enabling anonymous communication. It directs Internet traffic through a free, worldwide, volunteer overlay network, consisting of more than six thousand relays,to conceal a user’s location and usage from anyone performing network surveillance or traffic analysis. Using Tor makes it more difficult to trace a user’s Internet activity.</p>
<h1 id="who-is-tails-intended-for">Who is tails intended for?</h1>
<p>As the tails website states (<a href="https://tails.boum.org/)">https://tails.boum.org/)</a>. Tails is intended for Activists who use Tails to hide their identities, avoid censorship, and communicate securely. Journalists and their sources use Tails to publish sensitive information and access the Internet from unsafe places. Domestic violence survivors use Tails to escape surveillance at home. You whenever you need extra privacy in this digital world.</p>
<h1 id="requirements">Requirements</h1>
<ol>
<li>A computer (minimum of 2GB ram , 64-bit x86–64 compatible processor)</li>
<li>A usb stick with 8GB+ of space</li>
</ol>
<p>Read more <a href="https://tails.boum.org/doc/about/requirements/index.en.html">https://tails.boum.org/doc/about/requirements/index.en.html</a></p>
<h1 id="installation">Installation</h1>
<p>Back up all your files USB files as they will get deleted!</p>
<p>The first thing you will have to do is to head to <a href="https://tails.boum.org/install/index.en.html">https://tails.boum.org/install/index.en.html</a>
Now select your operating system</p>
<p>Ill walk you through the installation for windows and linux.
This should probably bethe same with linux
After you have clicked on the windows logo you should be prompted with the requirements and a step by step guide.</p>
<p>The first thing you will have to do is to download the tails usb image.</p>
<p>After that i highly recommend that you verify your download</p>
<p>Just click on select and select it.</p>
<p>Now you will have to download balena etcher. Just click on download balena etcher and double click the installer.</p>
<p>At this moment plug in your usb (if you have any important files on the usb you have to back the up or they will be lost)</p>
<p>Now click the flash from file button and select the file you downloaded (it ends in .img)</p>
<p>Click the Select target button to select your USB stick.</p>
<p>And now select flash.</p>
<p>This could take a while so just sit back and relax.</p>
<h1 id="using-tails">Using tails</h1>
<p>After your installation is finished just reboot your computer and hit F12 or F2 depending on your computer.</p>
<p>Now you should see a screen thats says something like please select your boot device. You will have to select your usb and hit enter</p>
<p>Now you should see the grub loader</p>
<p>Select Tails and hit enter</p>
<p>Now you should be booted into tails</p>
<p>You will probably see a screen that looks something like this</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/../assets/tails.webp" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<p>Here you will have to set your language and region. We can also press on the + icon to add a admin password mac address anonymization etc. I will just put the admin password and the unsafe browser. You can select anything you want. However remember that changing some of these settings will make you less anonymous.</p>
<p>Once you are ready select start tails</p>
<p>Now you will see</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/../assets/tails2.webp" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<p>Here you can select anything you want. I will just select the first option.</p>
<p>Now you should see this:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/../assets/tails3.webp" type="" alt=""  /></p>
<p>GG you did it. One more step though</p>
<p>I like to have a persistent volume so that i don’t lose all my files when i reboot. To do that open the configure persistent volume app and follow the steps there.</p>
<p>That’s it for now</p>
<p>*<strong>If you enjoyed this article consider <a href="../../donate">supporting me</a></strong></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
