<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on 4rkal</title>
    <link>https://4rkal.com/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on 4rkal</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 11:54:29 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://4rkal.com/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to deploy django to production</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/django-prod/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 11:54:29 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/django-prod/</guid>
      <description>I recently deployed my very own django application to production. The website is called videiro.com and was developed in django + HTML/CSS/JS + Tailwind.&#xA;Setup I am using a debian 12 server which will expose my application via cloudflare tunnels. All of the static files are being served via nginx and the Django project is being ran by gunicorn.&#xA;In this guide I will show you how I set this up.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python for Complete Beginners</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 20:52:42 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/python/</guid>
      <description>Why you should use Python. Going over the basics of Python.&#xA;In this course/article I will be talking about why someone should use Python. Later on, I will be tackling the basics of Python. But let&amp;rsquo;s start by explaining what coding is.&#xA;What is coding? Coding means writing instructions for computers and a finished set of instructions is known as a program. Computer programs control everything from smartphones to space rockets.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automating your web browser with selenium</title>
      <link>https://4rkal.com/posts/selenium/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 21:23:38 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://4rkal.com/posts/selenium/</guid>
      <description>Selenium is a very good skill to have as you can automate almost everything that you can do with a web browser.&#xA;In this tutorial, we’ll learn how to use Python and Selenium to automate a web browser. This is an updated version of my previous article which unfortunately doesn&amp;rsquo;t work anymore. If you’re a complete beginner, read my python article to understand the basics. (https://4rkal.com/posts/python/)&#xA;What is selenium? Selenium is an open source umbrella project for a range of tools and libraries aimed at supporting browser automation.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
